In this video, we are going to look at the second garbage collection technique, stop
在本视频中，我们将了解第二种垃圾收集技术，停止
and copy. In stop-and-copy garbage collection memory is organized into two
然后复制。在停止复制垃圾收集中，内存被组织为两个
areas. We have an old space that's used for allocation and so all of the data that
区域。我们有一个旧空间用于分配，因此所有数据
the program is currently using lives in this area called the old space. And then
该计划目前正在使用这个被称为旧空间的区域的生命。然后
there's a new space which is reserved for the garbage collector. And so, this is not
有一个新的空间是为垃圾收集器预留的。所以，这不是
used by the program, it's just for the GC. And so the first decision in stop-and-copy
由程序使用，它仅供GC使用。所以停止复制的第一个决定
garbage collection is that the program can only use half the space. And there are
垃圾回收是指程序只能使用一半的空间。而且还有
some techniques more advance techniques, for stop-and-copy garbage collection that
某些技术更高级，用于停止和复制垃圾收集，这些垃圾收集
allow the program to use more than half the space. So, this isn't as bad as it
允许程序使用一半以上的空间。所以，这并不是那么糟糕
sounds but fundamentally, a fairly significant fraction of the space has to
听起来不错，但从根本上讲，相当大一部分空间必须
be reserved for the garbage collector. Now the way allocation works is that there's a
保留给垃圾收集器。现在分配的方式是有一个
heat pointer here in the old space and everything to the left of the heat pointer
热指针位于旧空间中，以及热指针左侧的所有内容
is currently in use. This is where all the objects have already been allocated in
当前正在使用中。这是已经在其中分配了所有对象的位置
this area that I just shaded here in red. And then when it comes time to allocate a
我刚才在这里用红色阴影的这个区域。然后，当需要分配一个
new object, we simply allocate it at the heap pointers. So, the heap pointer will
新对象，我们只需在堆指针处分配它。因此，堆指针将
simply bump up and some block of space will be allocated to a, the next object
简单地撞上去，一些挡路的空间就会分配给一个，下一个物体
that we want to do. And it will just keep marching through the old space allocating
这是我们想要做的。它将继续在旧的空间分配中行进
as you allocate more objects. Okay, so allocation just advances the heap pointer
随着您分配更多的对象。好的，所以分配只是推进堆指针
so one of the advantages, actually, of stop-and-copy is a very simple and fast
因此，实际上，停止和复制的优势之一是非常简单和快速
allocation strategy. Now eventually, of course, if we allocate over and over
分配策略。最终，当然，如果我们一遍又一遍地分配
again, we're going to fill up the old space and so garbage collection will start
同样，我们要填满旧空间，因此垃圾收集将开始
GC, will start when the old space is full. And what it's going to do is going to copy
GC，将在旧空间已满时启动。它要做的就是复制
all the reachable objects, all the reachable objects from the old space into
所有可达对象，将旧空间中的所有可达对象放入
the new space. And the beauty of this idea is that when you copy the reachable
新的空间。这个想法的美妙之处在于，当你复制可达的
objects, the garbage is left behind. So, you simply pickup all the data that you're
对象时，垃圾就会留在后面。因此，您只需获取您正在处理的所有数据
using and move it over to the new space and all the junk that you didn't need
使用并将其移动到新的空间和所有不需要的垃圾
anymore is left behind in the old space. And then, after you copy stuff to the new
更多的东西被留在了老地方。然后，在您将内容复制到新的
space first of all since you left the garbage behind, you're using less space
空间首先，自从你把垃圾留在身后，你使用的空间就更少了
than you did before the collection. So, there's some space available now in the
比你在收藏之前做的更多。所以，现在有一些空余的空间
new space for allocating new objects. And then, you simply swap the roles of the old
用于分配新对象的新空间。然后，你简单地交换一下旧的角色
and new space. So, the old and new spaces are reversed what was old becomes the new,
和新的空间。所以，旧的和新的空间颠倒了，旧的变成了新的，
and what was new becomes the old, and then the program resumes. So, let's take a look
新的就变成了旧的，然后程序又恢复了。那么我们来看一看，
at a quick example here just to get a idea of how this works. Let's say we have our
这里有一个简单的例子，只是想了解一下它是如何工作的。让我们假设我们有我们的
old space over here, this is the old space, and we have one root which is this
这里是老空间，这是老空间，我们有一个根，那就是这个
object A. And so what we're going to do, well we're going to make a copy of all the
对象A，所以我们要做的是，我们要复制所有
objects reachable from A. We're gonna move them over to the new space. And what
可以从A到达的物体我们要把它们搬到新的地方。还有什么
that's going to look like, well, here it is, afterward. But let's trace it out. So,
这看起来就像，嗯，这就是，之后的样子。不过，让我们把它查出来。所以,
we started A, we follow pointers from A, we can see there's a pointer to C, okay,
我们从A开始，沿着从A开始的指针，我们可以看到有一个指向C的指针，好的，
so C is going to be reachable and there's a pointer to F , okay. And then F points
所以C是可达的，有一个指向F的指针。然后是F点
back to A, and that's all the reachable objects so we copy them. And notice when
返回到A，这是所有可到达的对象，所以我们复制它们。并注意什么时候
we copy them, we also copy their pointers, and now the pointers have all been
我们复制它们，我们也复制它们的指针，现在指针都
changed. So, in the copy of A, it now points to the copy of C, okay. And of
变化。所以，在A的副本中，它现在指向C的副本，好的。以及
course, C will point to the copy of F and there's a little issue here, this line is
当然，C会指向F的副本，这里有一个小问题，这一行是
not in the right place so it should look like that. And then F points back to the
位置不对，所以应该是这样的。然后F指向后面的
copy of A. So, what we know, when the object and move their pointers and we
那么，我们所知道的，当对象和指针移动时，我们
adjust them so that we've really copied the whole graph of objects over to the
调整它们，以便我们真正将整个对象图复制到
news space. Now, we're using less space so there's some free space here, okay. And
新闻空间。现在，我们使用的空间更少了，所以这里有一些空闲的空间，好吧。和
now, this will become the old space. This now our old space and this is now the new
现在，这里将成为旧的空间。这是我们的旧空间，现在是新的
space which we will use for the next garbage collection. To summarize the
我们将用于下一次垃圾收集的空间。总结一下
discussi on so far, one of the essential problems in stop-and-copy is to make sure
到目前为止，讨论停止复制的一个基本问题是确保
that we find all the reachable objects and we saw this same problem with
我们找到了所有可到达的对象，我们看到了同样的问题
mark-and-sweep garbage collection. Now, the thing that really distinguishes
标记和清除垃圾收集。现在，真正与众不同的是
stop-and-copy is that we're going to copy these objects. So, when we find a
停止复制就是我们要复制这些对象。所以，当我们找到一个
reachable object we copy it into the new space. And that means that we have to find
可到达的对象，我们将其复制到新空间中。这意味着我们必须找到
and fix all the pointers that point to that object and this is actually not
并修复指向该对象的所有指针，而这实际上不是
obvious how to do, alright. Cuz when you find an object, of course, you can't see
很明显该怎么做，好吧。因为当你找到一个物体的时候，你当然看不到
all the pointers that point into that object. So, how are we going to do that?
所有指向该对象的指针。那么，我们要怎么做呢？
Well, here is an idea. Well, we copy the object, we're going to store in the old
好吧，我有个主意。嗯，我们复制对象，我们要存储在旧的
version of it, it was called, a forwarding pointer to the new copy. So, let's take a
它的版本被称为指向新副本的转发指针。那么，让我们来看一看
look at what that would how that would, how that looks like. So we have our old
看看那会是什么样子，看起来是什么样子。所以我们有我们的旧的
space, we have our new space. And let's say, we discover some reachable object A
太空，我们有了新的空间。比方说，我们发现了一些可达的对象A
in the old space. So, what we're going to do is we're going to make a copy of it
在老地方。所以，我们要做的就是复制一份
over here in the new space and that's easy enough to do. But now what we're going to
在这里的新空间，这是很容易做到的。但现在我们要做的是
do is we're gonna take A and we're going to reuse its space and we're gonna store
我们要做的是拿A，我们要重新利用它的空间，我们要存储
what's called a forwarding pointer in it. So, we're going to, yeah, first of all,
这就是所谓的转发指针。所以，我们要，是的，首先，
we're going to mark somehow that this has been copied. So, this will have some
我们会以某种方式标记这是被复制的。所以，这个会有一些
special mark on it which I'll just, you know, indicate with here with a purple bar
上面有一个特殊的标记，你知道，我会在这里用一个紫色的线条来表示
something. This is we're marking someway so that we can tell this object has
某物。这是我们以某种方式标记的，这样我们就可以告诉这个物体
already been copied. And then at a. At a distinguished location in the object,
已经被复制了。然后在a.在对象中的显著位置，
we're going to store the forwarding pointer. And you can think of this as like
我们将存储转发指针。你可以把这个想象成这样
a forwarding address. So, if you know where somebody lives you can go to their
转发地址。所以，如果你知道某人住在哪里，你可以去他们的
house and if they have moved, you can ask for the forwarding address. And that's
如果他们搬家了，你可以问他们的转寄地址。那就是
exactly and then you can go off to their new house wherever they've wherever
没错，然后你就可以去他们的新房子，无论他们在哪里，无论他们在哪里
they've gone to and presumably find them. And so, that's what's going to happen
他们已经去了，大概找到他们了。所以，这就是将要发生的事情
here. If we have a pointer that points into this object later on and maybe much
这里。如果我们有一个稍后指向此对象的指针，可能会有更多
later on in the garbage collection, we may discover this pointer, we may follow this
稍后在垃圾收集中，我们可能会发现此指针，我们可能会遵循以下内容
pointer, find out it points in this object, realize that this object has moved
指针，找出它指向这个对象，意识到这个对象已经移动了
because we've marked it and the object was moved. And then we can use the forwarding
因为我们已经做了标记，而且物体被移动了。然后我们就可以使用转发
pointer to find out where the new object is and then update this pointer wherever
查找新对象所在位置的指针，然后在任何位置更新此指针
it is to point to the new object. Now, just like with mark-and-sweep, we still
它指向新对象。现在，就像标记和清扫一样，我们仍然
have the issue of how to implement the traversal of the object graph without
我有一个问题，那就是如何在没有对象图的情况下实现对象图的遍历
using any extra space. Again, when these garbage collection algorithms, they only
使用任何额外的空间。同样，当这些垃圾收集算法
get used, they only get run in low memory situations. And you can't assume that you
使用后，它们只在内存较低的情况下运行。你不能想当然地认为你
can build unbounded data structures to use with the garbage collectors. The garbage
可以构建无界数据结构以与垃圾收集器一起使用。垃圾
collector really needs to work in constants base. And now here is the idea
收集器确实需要在常量库中工作。现在的想法是这样的
that will, that is used in stop-and-copy algorithms to solve the problem. So, we're
那就是，在停止和复制算法中使用它来解决问题。所以，我们要
going partition in new space and this is just the new space here into three
在新的空间中进行分区，这就是这里的新空间，分为三个
contiguous regions. We're going to have we'll start with the one on the far right.
连续区域。我们将会有，我们将从最右边的那个开始。
We're going to have the empty region where we're allocating new objects. And there's
我们将拥有分配新对象的空白区域。而且还有
an allocation pointer that points to the beginning of that region. So this is the
指向该区域开始的分配指针。所以这就是
region that we're filling up with objects that we're copying over and this is just
我们正在用我们复制的对象填充的区域，这就是
empty unused space. Now, immediately to the left of that region are the objects
清空未使用的空间。现在，紧靠该区域左侧的是对象
that have already been copied, but not scanned, okay? This is copied and not
已经被复印了，但没有扫描，好吗？此文件已复制，并且未
scanned. And, what does that mean? Well, that means that the object has been copied
扫描过了。那是什么意思呢？嗯，这意味着这个物体已经被复制了
over. And so, we've actually, you know, made a copy of the object into the new
完毕。所以，我们实际上已经，你知道，把这个物体复制到新的
space. But we haven't yet looked at its pointers. We haven't yet looked at the
太空。但我们还没有看过它的要点。我们还没有看过
pointers inside the object to see where they go. And then, to the left of that,
对象内部的指针以查看它们的去向。然后，在它的左边，
are the objects that have been copied and scanned. These are objects that have been
是已复制和扫描的对象。这些是已经被
copied over. And we've also processed all the pointers inside of those obje cts. And
复制过来了。我们还处理了这些对象CTS中的所有指针。和
so, you can think of this area here, between the scanned pointer and the
所以，你可以在这里想一想，在扫描的指针和
allegation pointer, this is the work quest. So, these are the objects that
指控指针，这就是工作追求。所以，这些就是这些物体
still need to be processed. These are the objects that have been copied over but
还需要处理。这些是已经复制的对象，但是
might yet still point to objects that haven't been copied. And so, these are the
可能仍指向尚未复制的对象。所以，这些是
objects where we have to look at their pointers to see whether they point to
对象，我们必须查看它们的指针以查看它们是否指向
something that still needs to be copied over to finish the garbage collection.
仍需复制以完成垃圾收集的内容。
Returning to our little example, I'm now going to walk through how a stop-and-copy
返回到我们的小示例，我现在将演练如何停止和复制
garbage collector would collect this particular heap step by step. So, notice
垃圾收集器将逐步收集此特定堆。所以，请注意
that we only have one root object and it's A, okay, I just want to point out that A
我们只有一个根对象，它是A，好的，我只想指出A
has one pointer which points to object C, alright. So, at the very first step, what
有一个指针指向对象C，好的。那么，在最开始的第一步，
we're going to do is we're going to copy the A object over to the new space, okay.
我们要做的是把A物体复制到新的空间，好的。
And this is literally a byte for byte copy. So, we just take the bytes of A and
这实际上是一个字节接一个字节的拷贝。所以，我们只取A和A的字节
we do a copy without, you know, doing any inspection of the interior of the object,
我们复制的时候，你知道，没有对物体内部做任何检查，
over to the new space. And how's that work? Of course, our allocation pointer
去新的地方。这是怎么回事？当然，我们的分配指针
isn't in, initially right here at the beginning of the new space. And then we
不在这里，最初就在新空间的开始处。然后我们
add and we copy this one object over. And then that means allocating an object and
相加，我们就把这个物体复制过来。然后这意味着分配一个对象和
so now, the allocation pointer points to the first word of memory, beyond the
所以现在，分配指针指向内存的第一个字，超出
object that we just allocated, okay. Now what happens when we copy it over? Well,
我们刚刚分配的对象，好的。现在当我们把它复制过来的时候会发生什么呢？井,
because it is just a byte for byte copy, all the pointers in A still point to the
因为它只是字节复制的一个字节，所以A中的所有指针仍然指向
objects as they pointed to before which are the objects in old space. And notice
它们所指的对象是旧空间中的对象。并请注意
now that this copy of A points to the object C in the old space. The other thing
现在A的这个副本指向旧空间中的对象C。另一件事是
we do is we leave a forwarding pointer in the old copy of A. So, we mark A as having
我们所做的就是在A的旧副本中保留一个转发指针。因此，我们将A标记为
been copied, that's why it's grayed out. Indicates that this object has already
被复制了，这就是它灰显的原因。指示此对象已经
been moved. And that this dotted line here indicates that somewhere, we stored a
被搬走了。这里的虚线表明，我们在某个地方存储了一个
pointer to the new copy of A. And now, we're ready to begin the algorithms. And
指向A的新副本的指针，现在，我们准备开始算法。和
not ice that we have some objects here that have been copied but not scanned so
不是冰，我们这里有一些已经复制但没有扫描的对象
this is our work list. So, now it's going to repeatedly work off of those objects
这是我们的工作清单。所以，现在它将重复地工作在这些物体上
and how do we know they're objects in there? Well, we just compare the scan and
我们怎么知道它们是里面的物品呢？嗯，我们只是把扫描结果和
the allocation pointers. So, if they're if they are different, if there's an object
分配指针。所以，如果它们是不同的，如果有一个物体
in between the scan and the allocation pointer, at least one object between the
在扫描和分配指针之间，至少有一个对象位于
two, then there's work to do. There's an object that needs to be scanned that and,
两个，然后就有工作要做了。有一个物体需要扫描，
and possibly resulting in more objects being moved and allocated. So, what
并且可能导致更多的对象被移动和分配。那么，怎么了？
happens next? So, object, we, we process A, so we walk over A and find all the
接下来会发生什么？所以，对象，我们，我们处理A，所以我们遍历A，找到所有
pointers in A. And we copy any objects that it points to that haven't already
中的指针，并且我们复制它所指向的任何尚未
been moved. And so, before we said, you know, the A, this, this copy of A pointed
被搬走了。所以，在我们说之前，你知道，A，这个，这个A的复印件指向
to the old copy of C. So, now what we discover the C object, it hasn't been
到C的旧副本，所以现在我们发现的C对象，它还没有
moved, it's still in the old space. So, we copy it over and we update the pointer in
搬家了，它还在老地方。因此，我们复制它并更新指针
A to point to the new copy of C. Now, of course and then the scan pointer moves
A指向C的新副本。现在，当然，然后扫描指针移动
over A. We've scanned all the pointers in A, alright. And the allocation pointer
在A上，我们已经扫描了A中的所有指针，好的。和分配指针
also moves because we had to allocate space for C. And of course, C is just a
也会移动，因为我们必须为C分配空间。当然，C只是一个
byte for byte copy of what was in the old space. And so it, any pointers that it has
旧空间中内容的逐字节副本。所以它，它所拥有的任何指针
that point to objects that haven't been moved yet, moved yet just point back into
该指针指向尚未移动、已移动但仅指向返回的对象
the old space. So, in this case the object C points to the object F in the old space.
旧空间。因此，在这种情况下，对象C指向旧空间中的对象F。
And I probably should indicate here, here's the original dividing line, you
也许我应该在这里指出，这是原来的分界线，你
know, this is the old space over here and this is the new space over there, alright.
知道吗，这是这里的旧空间，这是那里的新空间，好吧。
And finally we mark C as having been copied, having been moved to the new space
最后，我们将C标记为已复制，已移动到新空间
and we left a forwarding pointer to it in case so we can fix any pointers that point
我们留了一个指向它的转发指针以防万一，这样我们就可以修复指向它的任何指针
to C that we come across in the future. And now we have to continue scanning
到我们将来遇到的C。现在我们必须继续扫描
objects that have been copied but not scanned. And we can see that there is an
已复制但未扫描的对象。我们可以看到有一个
object between the scan and the allocatio n pointer namely C and so we'll now
对象位于扫描和分配指针(即C)之间，所以我们现在
process all the pointers in C. Next, we scan C. And, we discover that it points to
处理C中的所有指针。接下来，我们扫描C，我们发现它指向
F. Which hasn't been moved yet and so we copy F over into the new space and we
它还没有被移动，所以我们把F复制到新的空间，我们
update the pointer in C. And now C has been copied and scanned, okay. So, the
更新C中的指针，现在C已经被复制和扫描，好的。所以呢，这个
scan pointer moves past C and of course, F again is a byte for byte copy and so all
扫描指针移过C，当然，F也是字节复制的字节，因此全部
it's pointers into old space are still pointing to old space, in particular F
指向旧空间的指针仍然指向旧空间，特别是F
points to A and the allocation pointer is moved again because we moved F, alright.
指向A，分配指针再次移动，因为我们移动了F。
And now, we have to process F. And this will be the last object that we move. And
现在，我们必须处理F，这将是我们移动的最后一个物体。和
what happens, well, we discover that F points to A, okay. And A is already marked
发生了什么，我们发现F指向A，好的。而且A已经被标记了
as having been moved and it has a forwarding pointer. So, instead of copying
因为它已经被移动，并且它具有转发指针。所以，与其复制
A again, we simply update the pointer in F that pointed to the old version of A to
同样，我们只需将F中指向A的旧版本的指针更新为
point to the copy of A, okay. And so, now F is completely scanned. All the pointers
指向A的副本，好的。所以，现在F完全被扫描了。所有的指针
in F have been processed. We didn't allocate any new objects so the allocation
F中的所有数据都已处理过。我们没有分配任何新对象，因此分配
pointer didn't move and now the scan pointer and the allocation pointer are
指针没有移动，现在扫描指针和分配指针
equal. There are no objects in between them and so our work list is empty and
平等。它们之间没有对象，所以我们的工作列表是空的
this is the garbage collected heap. This is a complete graph, a complete copy of
这是垃圾收集堆。这是一个完整的图表，一个完整的副本
its A, of the graph of reachable objects from the old space. So, now we're done and
它是来自旧空间的可达对象图的A。所以，现在我们做完了
we simply swap the role of the new and old space and we resume the program so that
我们只需交换新旧空间的角色，然后恢复该计划，以便
when the program starts running again, it will allocate out of this area and it'll
当程序再次开始运行时，它将分配出此区域，并且它将
be on the allocation pointer until it fills up what is now the old space, you
一直在分配指针上，直到它填满了现在的旧空间，您
know, and then this will be the new space that will be used for the next garbage
知道，然后这将是新的空间，将用于下一个垃圾
collection. Here's a pseudo code algorithm outlining how stop-and-copy garbage
收藏。这里有一个伪代码算法，概述了如何停止和复制垃圾
collection should work. So, while the scan and allocation pointers are different,
收集应该可以工作。因此，虽然扫描指针和分配指针不同，
remember, we keep running until the scan pointer catches up with the allocation
请记住，我们会一直运行，直到扫描指针赶上分配
pointer and they're equal. What we're going to do is we're going to look at the
指针，它们是相等的。我们要做的是我们要看看
object that is at the scan pointer. That we'll call that objec t , and then for
对象，该对象位于扫描指针处。我们称之为Objec T，然后
every pointer in O, we're going to do the following. We're going to find the object
O中的每个指针，我们将执行以下操作。我们要找到那个物体
O' that, that pointer points to. And then there are two cases. One is that there is
哦，那个，那个指针指向。然后是两个案例。其一是有
no forwarding pointer, alright. And if there's no forwarding pointer, then we
没有转发指针，好吧。如果没有转发指针，那么我们
have to copy that object to new space and that will involve allocating a new object
我必须将该对象复制到新空间，这将涉及到分配一个新对象
and updating the allocation pointer. Then we're going to set and here it says the
以及更新分配指针。然后我们要设置，这里写着
first word, they really shouldn't emphasize the first word. Set a word. So,
第一个词，他们真的不应该强调第一个词。定个词。所以,
it's a distinguished word, that's what's important. We have to know which word
这是一个杰出的词，这才是最重要的。我们必须知道哪个词
we're going to use and will always be the same word. But anyways, we set a word of
我们将使用并将永远使用同一个词。但不管怎样，我们定了一句话
the old object to point to the new copy. We mark the old object as copied. Mark old
指向新副本的旧对象。我们将旧对象标记为复制。标记为旧
object as copied, okay. So, that's so that we can tell if we ever come to a pointer
复制的物体，好的。这就是说，如果我们到达一个指针，我们就可以知道
to it again, we know it's already been moved and then we change p, the pointer,
再说一次，我们知道它已经被移动了，然后我们改变指针p，
to point to the new copy of O', alright. So, if there was, that's what we do if
指向O‘的新版，好吧。所以，如果有的话，这就是我们要做的
there is no forwarding pointer. And if there is a forwarding pointer, then we
没有转发指针。如果有转发指针，那么我们
simply update the pointer to point to the same place as the forwarding pointer. And
只需更新指针，使其指向与转发指针相同的位置。和
we just repeat this loop over and over again until we've scanned all the copied
我们只是一遍又一遍地重复这个循环，直到我们扫描完所有拷贝的
options.
选项。